GIORGIO POMETTINI

PROGRAMMER

DETAILS

ADDRESS:

00177 Rome, Italy

EMAIL:

giorgio.pomettini@gmail.com

PHONE:

(0039) 320 5624877

NATIONALITY:

Italian

LINKS

WEBSITE/PORTFOLIO:

giorgiopomettini.eu

GITHUB:

github.com/pomettini

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/pomettini/

SKILLS

LANGUAGES (IN ORDER OF KNOWLEDGE)

C#

Rust

C/C++ Lua

Javascript

Python

SOFTWARE

Unity

Unreal Engine 4

Xcode

Visual Studio

Photoshop

Sketch Mava

TOOLS

Git

Perforce

Plastic SCM

LANGUAGES

ITALIAN:

Mother tongue

ENGLISH:

B2 (Written and spoken)

PROFILE

I'm a curious and creative person. I have been working in the game industry since 2012, starting as an artist and later becoming a programmer. Because of that, I have an eye for details and enjoy finding creative solutions to problems. In my spare time, I like to contribute to open-source projects on GitHub to improve my programming skills. I'm also a Game Jam enthusiast, having made more than two dozen games in these events.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

GAME PROGRAMMER (UNITY) AT DIGITALMOKA

June 2022 - Present

Working on card games for iOS and Android licensed by Dal Negro.

GAME PROGRAMMER (UNITY) AT THIRD KIND GAMES

March 2020 - March 2022

Working on <u>Blankos</u>: <u>Block Party</u>, a MMO where you collect and create custom characters based on toy figurines. I mainly focused on UI and audio implementation.

TEACHER, TUTOR AND TOOLS PROGRAMMER AT ACCADEMIA ITALIANA VIDEOGIOCHI

October 2018 - September 2019

Teaching history of Videogames, Lua scripting and Unreal Engine. Worked individually with more than 80 students between two different courses.

LEAD PROGRAMMER (UNITY) AT 101%

November 2015 - July 2017

Worked on <u>Fury Roads Survivor</u> (6+ million downloads on iOS/Android), Lino Freddolino (Poste Italiane), Platform Discovery (Eni).

UNITY DEVELOPER AT IV PRODUCTIONS

January 2015 - July 2015

Worked on Audio Rally Racing for PC/Mac/iOS and Riot Civil Unrest.

UNITY DEVELOPER AT REDBIT GAMES

November 2013 - April 2014

Worked on 3 advert-games with Unity: Advent Calendar 2013, Easter Calendar 2014, Caxi & Roll. 2+ million downloads on iOS/Android.

FREELANCE DEVELOPER & PUBLIC SPEAKER

2012 - Present

Clients: Philip Morris Italy, Interactive Project, Gamepix, Canvace, Just Funny Games, Lisari.

Been a speaker a Codemotion Rome, LEVEL UP, GameRome and Facebook Developer Group.

EDUCATION

GAME PROGRAMMING COURSE, ACCADEMIA ITALIANA VIDEOGIOCHI

2017 - 2018

Low-level Game Programming with C, C++ and GLSL. Fundamentals of OpenGL, Unreal Engine 4, Arduino, Python, Lua.

3D GRAPHICS COURSE, ACCADEMIA ITALIANA VIDEOGIOCHI

2011 - 2013

Realtime 3D Graphics with Maya, Mudbox, Photoshop, ZBrush.

CERTIFICATIONS

UNITY CERTIFIED DEVELOPER

2017 - 2019

Certificate ID: 201708UCD2713